If you can
如果年底之前
achieve more results
你能让自己的履历
by the end of the year,
更漂亮一些
we may be able to
过完新年
work together at the Supervision Office
也许我们就能在监察院
next year.
共事了
Thank you, I...
属下明
Where is the deserter from the 32nd Army?
三十二军的逃兵在几号
I'm here to make a deal with you.
我来找你谈笔交易
This confession
这份认罪书上
needs a thumbprint.
需要一个人的手印
If you can get it done tonight,
如果今晚你能办成
I'll arrange
我会办妥
your bail.
你的取保候审手续
Once out of jail,
出了监狱
you're free.
你就是自由人了
Whose thumbprint?
你要谁的手印
Mr. Hua, right?
华先生是吧
Do me a favor, please.
想麻烦你帮个忙
It's simple.
很简单
Just a thumbprint.
摁个手印就行了
What if I refuse it?
如果不呢
He's still breathing.
还有气儿
Captain.
队长
He's strangled unconscious by Hua Zhen
他被华桢勒晕过去了
and hasn't woken up.
还没醒
How did things go with the guards?
看守那边交代得怎么样
They're required to keep
我已经交代好他们
the mouth shut.
管好嘴了
Just bury him here.
就埋这儿吧
Bury?
埋了
What?
怎么了
He's not the first to be buried here.
这儿埋的人还少啊
But...
可
he's just unconscious.
可他只是晕过去了
He's a deserter.
一个逃兵
Who would care about him?
谁还记得他
Is this Mr. Wan?
是万兄吗
Hello,
万兄
this is Wei Dai...
我是魏岱
actually, Wei Fulai.
我是魏福来呀
I'm wondering
万兄
if you're still
不知万兄现在
working in the archives at the
还在陆大的档案室
Army University.
工作否
That's great.
太好了
I need a favor from you.
还是要请万兄帮忙啊
You have
这样
a student named Hua Zhen
有个学生叫华桢的
at the regular class.
正则班
Could you
你能不能
get me a copy
给我搞一张
of his ID photo?
他的证件照出来
In his
我要便装
casual clothes.
就要便装
Rest assured.
万兄请放心
I won't
你是知道我的
shortchange you
在钱方面
on the payment.
我一分都不会少你的
But be quick.
但时间要快
Thank you so much.
拜托万兄啊
The organization
组织破例
made an exception to confirm
确认了向远生的身份
that Xiang Yuansheng doesn't belong to us.
他的确不是我们的同志
Are you sure?
确定不是吗
He's not.
不是
What kind of evidence
那魏岱擎手上
does Wei Daiqing hold then?
到底有什么样的证据
Or
还是说
is he deliberately
他明知道向远生不是
misidentifying Yuansheng?
故意要张冠李戴
My biggest concern now
我现在最担心的是
is that Runjin's situation
润金同志的事情
might be linked to him.
和魏岱擎有关
At that time, you didn't know
那个时候你还不知道
Runjin was our man.
他是我们的同志
Xiang Yuansheng used his belt
向远生帮他止血的时候
to stop the bleeding
把自己的皮带
on Runjin's leg.
拴在他腿上
But up till now,
可是到现在
I still haven't
我还是没能
found Runjin.
找到润金同志
If he's
照这么说
taken away
如果张润金同志真的是
by Wei Daiqing,
被魏岱擎带走的
the belt could likely
皮带很有可能
be used as evidence.
会被当作证据
Yes,
对
but just as evidence.
但也只是当作证据
After all,
毕竟向远生
Xiang Yuansheng is not one of us.
不是我们的同志
Keeping a distance from him
既然不是
is the best protection.
我们跟他保持距离
This can
让魏岱擎
prevent Wei Daiqing from finding
抓不到任何把柄
anything substantial against him.
就是对他最好的保护
So, do not
所以在魏岱擎
act until
亮出他的牌之前
Wei Daiqing
你千万不要
shows his hand.
主动做任何事情
Understood.
知道了
Hua Liang visited the Fourth Station.
华梁来过四所
He said that was a casual visit,
他说想随便看看
but I know
但我知道他绝对不是
it's impossible.
简单地看看而已
If there's anything
如果有什么
the Fourth Station can assist with,
是四所能帮上忙的
may I?
我能帮忙吗
Would that be a breach of discipline?
这算违反组织纪律吗
Not at all.
当然不算
Regarding Xiang Yuansheng,
在向远生这件事情上
we're not different from
我们和华梁的目的
what Hua Liang wanna do.
是相同的
Thank you.
谢谢
You should go back.
快回去吧
I'll confirm a new meeting point
我会尽快安排一个
as soon as possible.
新的接头地点
Alright.
好
You know what Wei Daiqing did.
你知道魏岱擎做了什么
He's gonna be dismissed.
他会被撤职的
Even if the Shanghai Garrison Command
我知道淞沪警备司令部
is governed by the Ministry of Military Affairs,
归军政部管
there're other departments
但南京不是只有军政部
and many generals in Nanjing
也不是只有你父亲
besides your father.
一个中将
I believe that Captain Wei
队长得罪得了这个
can strike a balance.
肯定就能讨好那个
Of course he can.
魏队长当然不担心前途
But how about you?
但他会带你上船吗
Your police girlfriend
你那个警察女朋友
has been released.
已经放出去了
While detained here,
她关在这儿的时候
I didn't trouble her
我没为难她
or disturb her family.
也没惊扰到她的家人
Come in.
进来
Captain, I'm coming.
队长 您找我
Close the door.
把门关上
Listen, find the landlady
我要你去趟广州
who
给我把
provided us tips
提供线索那个房东太太
in Guangzhou,
解决掉
and keep her silenced permanently.
我要她永远闭嘴
Clear?
明白了吗
Got it.
明白了
Do your best.
好好干
I have higher hopes for you
相比高平顺
than Gao Pingshun.
我更看好你
Yes, sir.
是
Zhang Runjin
张润金
is a member of
是共产党
the CPC under Deng Mingyuan.
邓铭远的小组成员
I've tracked him
这名共产党
from Guangzhou
我追查他很久了
all the way to Shanghai.
从广州一直追到上海
This belt
这条皮带
was
是在我
taken off from his leg
逮捕张润金的时候
when he's arrested.
从他的腿上解下来的
He's stabbed with a dagger.
当时他腿部中刀
And someone
有人用这条皮带
used the belt
绑在他的腿上
to stop the bleeding.
为他止血
Seeing
我发现
the word inside,
这条皮带是
I suspect it's from Li Shunchang's store
南京李顺昌饰品店的
in Nanjing.
商品
So I personally went there
我亲自跑了一趟南京
and found out
发现
that it's bought by Hua Zhen's mother
这条皮带是华桢的母亲
for him.
买给华桢的
This
这个
is the testimony and the receipt
是老板李顺昌的证词
from the store owner.
这个是饰品店的单据
The belt can fully prove that
这条皮带完全可以证明
Hua Zhen is connected
华桢跟共产党
to the CPC.
是有关系的
That's when I started
我也是从那个时候开始
suspecting him.
怀疑上了他
Mr. Hua,
华先生
care to explain?
现在请你解释一下吧
Why you helped
为什么你要救
that Communist?
那名共产党
That gentleman
因为那位先生
protected a girl
保护了当时
living with me at the time
和我住在一起的女孩儿
and was injured as a result.
他也因此受了伤
So I felt that
所以我觉得
any help
我做出的
I offered
任何帮助他的行为
was merely human decency.
都是人之常情
I didn't know him
我并不认识他
or that
也不知道
he was a Communist.
他的共产党身份
You didn't know him?
你不认识他
You're saying
你的意思是说
Zhang Runjin was secretly
张润金在偷偷地
protecting the girl?
保护那个小女孩儿
Indeed, he was.
他的确是这样的
The girl he referred to
他说的小女孩儿
is Meng Duoci.
就是孟多慈
Her parents
孟多慈的父母
were closely tied with the CPC.
跟共产党交往甚密
Zhang Runjin
张润金
was obviously sent by the CPC
显然就是共产党
to protect her.
派来保护孟多慈的
That's why he never
他一直不敢抛头露面
dared to appear in the public.
恰好证明了这一点
What about you, Mr. Hua?
那么你呢 华先生
If you're not with the CPC,
如果你不是共产党
why did you
你为什么要
take in Meng Duoci?
收留孟多慈呢
The day I arrived in Shanghai,
我从南京来上海的当天
I intended to stay at Van Hwa Hotel
本打算住在文华饭店
but stumbled upon a murder scene.
碰巧遇到了凶杀案
Meng Duoci sought my help.
当时孟多慈向我求助
Out of sympathy,
出于同情
and since
我又正好
I had a month's vacation,
有一个月的假期
I agreed to stay
所以我答应留下来
and help her find the killer.
帮她找到凶手
She didn't know you.
她不认识你啊华先生
But facing trouble,
她出了事儿
why did she turn to you as a stranger
找一个陌生人帮忙
for help instead of the police,
她为什么不找警察
or report the case?
为什么不报案
Because she saw the killer
因为她看见凶手
wearing a police uniform.
有穿着警服
She didn't trust the police.
她不信任警察
So,
也就是说
you just
华先生你是
happened
碰巧
to encounter Meng Duoci
遇到了身逢绝境的
in a dire situation,
孟多慈
and happened
你碰巧
to save Zhang Runjin with severe injuries.
救了身负重伤的张润金
How then do you explain
那向远生这个化名
using the alias "Xiang Yuansheng"?
你又如何解释呢
There're 3 victims
文华饭店遇害的
at Van Hwa Hotel,
一共有三名
including Duoci's parents
除了孟多慈的父母之外
and a young man.
还有一名年轻男性
The household card for Xiang Yuansheng
向远生的户籍卡
was taken from him.
就是从他身上拿出来的
My family wouldn't agree with me
我的家人不会同意
investigating cases in Shanghai.
我在上海查案
If I used my real name
如果我用华桢这个名字
as a police officer,
当警察
they'd have known by the next day.
他们第二天就会知道
So, I used
所以我借用了
that household card.
向远生这张户籍卡
The photo
照片
was also tore off
也是从户籍卡上
from the card.
抠下来的
Captain Wei.
魏队长
Is the deceased Hua Zhen mentioned
华桢说的死者
He Youqing?
就是何友庆吗
He Youqing.
何友庆
The third victim at Van Hwa Hotel.
文华饭店的第三名死者
Unfortunately,
很不幸
also
也是一名
a Communist.
共产党
Is there any problem
那他现在说的
with what he's saying now?
有什么问题吗
The alias Xiang Yuansheng
向远生这个假身份
was prepared by the CPC
是共产党
for He Youqing.
为何友庆准备的
He died.
何友庆死了
Hua Zhen picked up this identity
华桢从何友庆身上
from him
捡到了这个身份
and used it.
用了这个身份
His statement
参谋长这个说法
has no problems
没有任何问题
although slightly flawed.
虽说有一点小毛病
Since Meng Duoci has disappeared
因为孟多慈失踪了
and He Youqing is dead,
何友庆死了
no one can prove his story
没有任何人能证明
true or false.
他这个说法的真或假
At least it sounds reasonable.
至少听上去合情合理
But,
但是
in Guangzhou,
我在广州
I found these documents
从张润金
in an apartment rented by Zhang Runjin
为孟家租的公寓里
for the Mengs.
搜到了这些
A month ago,
我发现一个月前
Zhang had rented
张润金在广州
an apartment in Guangzhou for the Meng family.
给孟家租了一套公寓
I found these documents
我在公寓里
in the apartment.
搜到了这些证件
The CPC's plan
共产党的计划
was originally to relocate
原本是把孟家
the Mengs to Guangzhou,
转移到广州
where they had rented a new house
为他们租了新的房子
and arranged new identity documents
安排了新的身份证明
and even new jobs.
连新的工作都找好了
One of the documents
其中一份身份证明上
read
写的是
"Xiang Yuansheng",
向远生
with a photo of Hua Zhen himself.
照片是华桢本人
If
请问
he is not a Communist,
如果华桢不是共产党
why would he be included
为什么共产党的计划里
in the plan?
包括他
That day
诸位长官
in Nanjing
那天在南京
when I went to arrest Deng Mingyuan,
我去逮捕邓铭远的时候
I personally saw
曾亲眼看见
Hua Zhen talking
华桢和邓铭远
with him in a room.
在房间里交谈
The next day,
第二天
Hua Zhen hurried to Shanghai.
他就急匆匆地去了上海
Why?
为什么
Because he wasn't
因为他根本
just going on a trip.
不是去游玩的
He was on a mission.
他是去执行任务的
He didn't just
他根本就不是
find the documents
从何友庆身上
on He Youqing.
捡到的证件
But the new identity
向远生这个身份
was exactly prepared for him!
根本就是为华桢准备的
He is the Communist sent by
他就是邓铭远派来的
Deng Mingyuan!
共产党
Hua Zhen.
华桢
How do you explain this document?
这份证件你怎么解释
My mom doesn't even remember
我妈妈根本不记得
making a belt
她在这家店
for Hua Zhen at that store.
给华桢做过皮带
I request
所以我要申请
a delay in the interrogation.
延缓后面的审讯
I need time
我需要时间
to verify this evidence.
核实这项证据
Set aside the belt for now.
皮带暂且不论
But what about the final document?
最后那份证件如何解释
It's incriminating.
那是致命的证据
Regarding this,
关于这个证件
we truly have no evidence
我们确实没有证据
to refute it.
去否认
Nor can I admit to it.
但是我也不可能承认
But if other evidence
可是其他的证据
is flawed,
如果出了错
you must give me time
你总得给我点儿时间
to verify it, right?
去核实吧
It's not
现在毕竟
an official trial yet.
不是正式的审讯
Hua Zhen must not be
我不可能让华桢
brought to the military court in Nanjing.
回南京上军事法庭啊
But during the hearing,
可是会审的时候
he's already admitted
华桢已经承认
the belt was his.
这条皮带是他的了
Denying it now
现在否认
seems quite far-fetched.
颇为牵强啊
My dad sent me here
我爸爸这次派我来上海
not to ascertain
不是让我来确定
who owns this belt.
这条破皮带到底是谁的
It's irrelevant.
它是谁的并不重要
But I must bring Hua Zhen
重要的是我要带华桢
back to home.
回南京回家
Besides, Uncle Tong.
再说了佟叔叔
My dad wouldn't want Hua Zhen
我爸爸也不希望华桢
to get into trouble on your turf,
在您的地盘上出事儿啊
right?
是不是
How much time do you need?
你要多长时间
Three days.
三天
Hua Liang.
华梁
I understand you're fighting for time.
我明白你要争取时间
We can help
这个面子
your family
我想参加会审的人
at the hearing,
可以给华家
but that's as far as it goes.
但仅此而已了
At this point,
现在这种情况
no one will dare
无论你去找任何人帮忙
to vouch for Hua Zhen
都会牵扯人家
without
根本不可能
implicating themselves.
有人敢出面担保华桢
I understand.
我知道
But no matter what,
但是无论如何
I'll do everything possible
我都要为我弟弟
for my brother.
尽一切可能
Sorry,
二位
but
真不好意思
I really can't let you in.
我真不能放你们进去
My son is an officer here!
我儿子在里面做长官
An officer?
做长官
Yes.
是啊
What's his name?
那您儿子叫什么名字呀
Wei Fulai.
魏福来呀
Wei Fulai?
魏福来
Captain,
队长
do you know them at the entrance?
刚才那俩人你认识啊
No.
不认识啊
Fulai...
福来
Didn't we agree
不是说好了
you'd call ahead?
提前打电话吗
Your mom really wanted to see you.
你妈实在想看看你啊
That's fine.
好好好
Just don't show up
以后不要
unannounced next time,
不打招呼就出来
okay?
行不行
This is the liquor
这是你爸爸
your dad brought from home.
专门从家里带的酒
It's your favorite from
就是你在溧岭的那时候
when you were in Liling.
最喜欢喝的那种白酒
Want to have a couple of drinks
你要不要跟你爸爸
with your dad?
喝两杯啊
I don't usually drink.
我平时不喝酒
I don't have the glasses for it.
家里没准备杯子
Aren't there a few there?
那不是有几个杯子呢
Those
那是
are for drinking coffee, Shanghai style.
上海人喝咖啡用的杯子
Fulai,
福来啊
your mom and I
我和你妈妈
came from Liling mainly because
从溧岭过来看你
we're worried
主要是担心你
you're not adjusting well.
不适应这边
I've been here a year.
来了一年了
I'm the Captain of the
我现在是侦查队
investigation team.
队长
I've adjusted fine.
倒也没有什么不适应
But
但是
you were transferred
你是从其他地方
from elsewhere.
调过来的呀
You're not one of their own.
不算他们自己人哪
I don't need
我不需要成为
to be that.
他们自己人
To be honest,
说实话
I look down on most of them,
我挺瞧不上这帮人的
especially those who climb the ranks
尤其是那些靠人脉
through background.
靠背景上位的
I'm smarter
我比他们大多数人
than most of them,
都要聪明得多
and I know it.
我很清楚这一点
What I lack
我所差的
is merely the background
只是他们拥有的出身
they possess.
和背景而已
Are you still bitter
你还在怨恨
about the Army Department incident?
陆军署那件事
Not bitter,
不怨恨
just dissatisfied.
是不甘心
I've passed the exam
那年我考进
for the Ministry of Military Affairs.
军政部陆军署
But a bureaucrat's son
那个当官的儿子
has taken my spot by dark box operation,
开后门抢了我的位置
sending me
把我打发到
to that unfortunate post in Nanchang.
南昌行营那种倒霉地方
The airfield fire happened,
南昌机场失火
dissolving the investigation department.
调查科解散
Lieutenant Colonel,
中校啊
the promised rank,
说好的中校
has gone.
没了
You factory workers
你们酒厂工人
can't comprehend these.
根本不懂这些
Don't offer me
以后不要再
advice anymore.
跟我提建议了
Fulai,
福来啊
we're buying tickets
明天我就和你妈妈
to go back tomorrow.
买票回去了
If not necessary,
以后没什么事
we won't come again.
我们就不来了
Dad,
爸
I've changed my name.
我改名字了
Next time when you call,
以后打电话的时候
remember
务必要记着
I'm not Wei Fulai,
不要叫我魏福来
but Wei Daiqing.
要叫我魏岱擎
Sir, have you
先生以前
bought our products?
买过我们牌子吗
Heard of the brand.
听说过
What type
您需要
of shoes do you need?
什么类型的鞋子啊
I can recommend some.
我可以帮您推荐
I'm...
我
just looking around.
我就过来看看样子
It doesn't work.
买鞋不能光看样子
You need to try them on.
还是得上脚试一下
Our shoes
我们的鞋子
are imported from Paris,
是法国巴黎进口的
patronized
在巴黎
by the
都是一些名媛绅士
elite and
上流社会的人
high society there.
来光顾我们品牌的
The pair you're holding
您手上拿的这双
is made from premium calf leather,
是上等的小牛皮
so the price is...
所以价格也会
I didn't ask about it.
我没问你价格
I want this material,
我就要这种材质
but the style
但是外表样式
should be more subdued.
要低调一些
It doesn't
不然
fit where
不符合我即将
I'm going otherwise.
出席的那种场合
Let me find you
我马上帮您
a classic pair
找一双经典款
to try on.
您试一下
Pingshun!
平顺
What's your shoe size?
平时穿鞋穿多大码
About the same as yours.
和队长您差不多
Perfect.
太好了
This pair has been with me for 3 years.
这双鞋跟了我三年
Now they're yours!
传给你
You
怎么
don't like them?
还嫌弃
Thank you.
谢谢队长
Any news
最近
from Mr. Hua Liang
我们的华秘书
lately?
有什么动静吗
The guys tailing him
盯梢的兄弟
haven't reported anything.
没有报告他有动静
He should still be in the hotel.
应该还在酒店里
I'll check on him later.
一会儿我去看看
He just wanna
他不就是想
make a fuss over the belt.
利用皮带做文章吗
Alright,
没关系
I've already requested
我已经申请了
surveillance on him.
对他的监控
Even if he knows
就算是他
you're monitoring,
发现你在监视他
it doesn't matter.
也没事儿
Keep me updated
他见什么人
on his meetings.
随时向我汇报
Has the belt store owner from Nanjing
南京那个饰品店老板
boarded the train yet?
上火车了吗
On his way.
已经在来的路上了
Mr. Hua,
华秘书
should we deal with the people
门口侦查队的人
from the investigation at the door?
要不要我们处理一下
They have
他们有
permission from the review committee.
会审委员会的许可
Don't ask for trouble on our own.
处理他们只会自找麻烦
But they...
可是他们
I know.
我知道
After they know
如果侦查队
what I wanna do,
发现我要做什么
Wei Daiqing will come to me.
魏岱擎就会来找我
Let's give him that chance.
那我们就给他这个机会
Do you
华秘书
have a plan?
您是有什么安排吗
Once the store owner
那个饰品店老板
arrives,
到了之后
tell him to meet me in the cafe
安排他在一楼咖啡厅
on the first floor.
跟我见面
Right under their noses?
就在他们眼皮底下
Yes, absolutely.
对 就在他们眼皮底下
Go ask them
去问问他们
if they'd like to join me for lunch.
想不想跟我共进午餐
Mr. Hua would like to invite you
华秘书想请几位
to join him for lunch.
一起共进午餐
Are you available?
不知是否有时间
I appreciate it.
谢谢华秘书好意
But no need.
不用了
Please tell him
也请你转告华秘书
that we're here
我们在这儿
on official duty.
也是因为执行公务
If any inconvenience,
如果打扰他了
we apologize.
很抱歉
Pingshun,
顺哥
someone's out.
出来个人
Is it Mr. Hua?
是华秘书吗
No.
不是他
Go to sleep. I'll keep watch.
睡吧 我盯着
Who is it?
谁呀
Captain Chen.
陈队长
Mr. Hua?
华先生
What brings you here?
您怎么来了 请进
Sorry for disturbing you so late.
很抱歉这么晚打扰你
Here's the thing,
是这样
last time you mentioned
上次你跟我说
that I can come to you
如果有什么需要帮忙的
if in need of help.
我可以来找你
Is Hua Zhen in trouble?
华桢出事了
Not at the moment.
暂时没有
But I do
但眼下
have a favor to ask.
确实有一事相求
Excuse me.
华秘书
Mr. Li.
李老板
Have a seat.
请坐
Please.
快
Thank you.
谢谢啊
How was
怎么样
your journey here?
这一路上顺利吗
Good.
顺利顺利
We've met before in Nanjing.
咱们在南京见过
Indeed.
那是
Who in Nanjing
您华秘书
doesn't
那南京城里
know Mr. Hua?
哪个不认识你
I invited you mainly
这次把您请来
because of
主要是为了
my brother's situation.
我弟弟的事情
Mr. Hua!
华秘书
He...
他在您
Sorry to bother.
打扰了
Captain Wei,
怎么
join us
魏队长也有雅兴
in coffee?
来喝杯咖啡啊
Mr. Hua,
华秘书
I've
我向
applied to the provisional
临时军法委员会委员
military tribunal
申请了对您的
for restrictions on you.
某些限制
You shouldn't
您真的不可以
meet anyone
在会审之前
involved
就和任何
in the case before the hearing.
和本案相关的人员会谈
He's my guest.
这是我请来的客人
Mr. Li?
李老板
He is our witness.
李老板是我们的证人
You know
这次的会审
this isn't
是不是真正的法庭审判
a real trial.
你心里清楚
Stop playing games with me.
少跟我来这套
How about
华秘书
negotiating
其实您可以
with the investigation team?
和侦查队谈判的
If you can persuade Hua Zhen
您看这样好不好
to put his fingerprint
如果您能够让华桢
on the confession
在认罪书上盖手印
stating
且这个认罪书
he's a
一定要写明
compatriot
他就是
of Deng Mingyuan,
邓铭远的同党的话
I can immediately
我现在立刻就可以
request the tribunal
向审判委员会申请
to classify him
把华桢列为
as a regular political prisoner.
普通的政治犯来判
Mr. Hua,
华秘书
you have one day
你有一天的时间
to think about it...
进行考虑
Thank you,
我谢谢你啊
but I don't need a day.
用不了一天的时间
I can tell you now.
我现在就可以答复你
You won't get anything from me.
你什么都拿不到
Wait...
不是
Mr. Hua!
华秘书
Captain Wei.
魏队长
Not only will you
你这次不光
get nothing,
什么都拿不到
but you also need
你还要把李老板
to reimburse Mr. Li's train fare
从南京来上海的火车票
from Nanjing to Shanghai.
全都给我报销了
Not a penny less.
一分钱都不能少
Stop here.
你别进来了
Just stay at the door.
你就门口待着
Here.
来
You've asked for 3 days.
你们要了三天时间
How's it going?
怎么样
Any progress?
有什么进展没有
Going through all this trouble
为了让我摁手印
to get a fingerprint,
还专门找个人过来帮忙
you must be desperate.
你也是够辛苦的
Where would you find such a person?
哪有这样的人呢
Even if
你找
you searched each and every
满淞沪警备司令部的
cell here,
牢房
you couldn't find anyone willing.
也找不出这样一个人来
Mr. Hua,
华先生
I consider myself
我自认为我自己
a hard worker,
是一个很努力的人
but I've realized
可是这些年做事
something over the years.
我忽然悟出了一个道理
Success doesn't just
很多事情进展顺利
come from efforts,
其实并不在于人为
it's about seizing the moment.
在于顺势而为
I have to say,
不好意思
the advantage this time
这回这势啊
is mine.
在我这儿
How's Zhang Runjin?
张润金现在怎么样了
Gosh.
不容易
You finally admit
你终于承认
that he's your comrade?
他是你的同志了
Where is he now?
他现在人在哪儿
Honestly,
说实话啊
I admire him.
我挺钦佩这个人的
He got himself seriously injured
为了保护一个小女孩儿
protecting a little girl.
把自己伤成那样
But I'm also grateful.
不过我也挺感激他的
Without him,
如果不是他
I wouldn't have found you.
我就找不到你
Oh yes,
对对对
from the detention center,
你从看守所
head west
往西走
down a small path.
有一条便道
Continue along that path
顺着那条便道
all the way
一直走下去
beyond Puhuitang,
过了蒲汇塘
and you'll find a wasteland.
你就会发现一块儿荒地
Dig down three feet,
往下挖三尺
and that's where he is.
他就在那儿
Probably reeking by now.
不过可能已经臭了
You're luckier than him,
你比他幸运多了
you know?
你知道吗
People are
时时刻刻
always watching you!
有人在关注着你
Why?
凭什么
If it weren't
要不是因为
for the name Hua Zhen,
华桢这个名字
you'd just be
你的结局
another hole
也不过是那块儿荒地里
in that wasteland.
多加一个坑
Everyone.
诸位
This is
今天
the second interrogation session.
算是我们第二次审讯
Due to Mr. Hua's
因为华秘书
objections
对皮带这个证据
on the belt,
提出了异议
requesting verification,
要求核实
we
所以
granted a three-day extension.
我们宽限了三天的时间
Mr. Hua.
华秘书
How about your verification?
你核实的情况怎么样了
I'm sorry
真是 太抱歉了
for the delay,
耽误了大家
and thank you all for your patience.
这么多宝贵的时间
My mother
我母亲啊
spent two full days searching our home
在家里面找了足足两天
but couldn't find the receipt
也没有找到这张
for this belt.
皮带的收据
Do you have the receipt?
你有收据吗
No.
没有
We have 3 men in our family.
我们家有三位男士
My mother shops at different stores
母亲会去不同的店铺
for our belts.
给我们买皮带
Sorry to interrupt.
不好意思二位华少爷
But the word
其实这个皮带的
"Shunchang"
皮带头上
inside the belt
烙印着顺昌两个字
has served as conclusive evidence.
就已经是铁证了
I explained this
上次庭审的时候
during the last trial.
我已经解释过了
Have you
难道二位
forgotten?
忘了吗